<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-01-16T17:24:14-06:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">Web dev</title><link href="/2021/01/16/Web-Dev.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Web dev" /><published>2021-01-16T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-01-16T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>/2021/01/16/Web%20Dev</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2021/01/16/Web-Dev.html">&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of this week, in my pursuit of finding a company name worthy of my exponentially growing endeavors, I started looking for domain names to start building my brand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried looking for a clever name that was uniquely personal and could not come up with an easy to remember domain. To my surprise, my full name(dot)com was available and I could not pass up the opportunity to have a clean domain name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, began my foray into web development at the very least. I have started building my website on the Jekyll platform that I hope will serve as a good starting point into static website development, to webapps and to start documenting the learning process as I learn many different frameworks I was not exposed to in my university studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Abel&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">At the beginning of this week, in my pursuit of finding a company name worthy of my exponentially growing endeavors, I started looking for domain names to start building my brand.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">web apps</title><link href="/2021/01/16/Web-Apps.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="web apps" /><published>2021-01-16T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-01-16T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>/2021/01/16/%20Web%20Apps</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2021/01/16/Web-Apps.html">&lt;p&gt;I owe this webapp idea to my dad who brought up an idea for a simple construction calculator to figure out different specs for simple construction calculations. The challenges will come with my lack of experience in webapp frameworks like react and xamarin. 
I have choosen to go ahead and start learning flutter for its native ui elements and cross platform ability since the mobile device of preference I use is android and my fathers iOS device.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I owe this webapp idea to my dad who brought up an idea for a simple construction calculator to figure out different specs for simple construction calculations. The challenges will come with my lack of experience in webapp frameworks like react and xamarin. I have choosen to go ahead and start learning flutter for its native ui elements and cross platform ability since the mobile device of preference I use is android and my fathers iOS device.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Intro to android dev</title><link href="/2021/01/16/Intro-to-Android-Dev.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Intro to android dev" /><published>2021-01-16T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-01-16T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>/2021/01/16/Intro%20to%20Android%20Dev</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2021/01/16/Intro-to-Android-Dev.html">&lt;p&gt;As I look for jobs and begin really searching for what I would like to accomplish in my software dev career, I have taken upon myself the challenge to expose myself to many different frameworks and languages I have yet to develop in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, my ideas are ever changing and growing every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From my guesstimation of difficulty I would like to develop a slew of different utilities in Kotlin for android.
From least to most difficult, these are the applications I would like to develop:
    *Car Maintenance Reminder Application/BillsToPay Reminder App
    *Workout Application utilizing different hypertrophy and strength training templates.
    *MovieMatch-tinder but for you and your SO to help choose movies yall would like to watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This should be a fun learning experience with many different aspects of android development to learn from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Abel&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">As I look for jobs and begin really searching for what I would like to accomplish in my software dev career, I have taken upon myself the challenge to expose myself to many different frameworks and languages I have yet to develop in.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Stonks</title><link href="/2021/01/16/Stonks.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stonks" /><published>2021-01-16T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-01-16T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>/2021/01/16/Stonks</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2021/01/16/Stonks.html">&lt;p&gt;Over the last month, stocks and cryptocurrency have put an interest in creating an auto trading bot I hope will further my experience in machine learning models and different API frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project will be built on python using pytorch and community sourced yahoo! finance api to gather stock data. This will be a daunting task as I have little experience in day trading stocks and cryptocurrencies as well as the difficulty in coming up with a great model to trade stock successfully.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Over the last month, stocks and cryptocurrency have put an interest in creating an auto trading bot I hope will further my experience in machine learning models and different API frameworks.</summary></entry></feed>